<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Réka Szentirmay | Creative Observatories</title>
    <link>/author/reka-szentirmay/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/reka-szentirmay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Réka Szentirmay</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:15:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Réka Szentirmay</title>
      <link>/author/reka-szentirmay/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting-up</title>
      <link>/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 10:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-08-24-start-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big day has come: the co-founders singed off the documents at the public notary and started the registration of a reproducible research start-up in Leiden.  We got a lot of support from our friends! Your encouragement gives us a lot of energy to accomplish our first milestones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As soon as our company is registered, we will even share its name with you:)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming days, we are launching demo versions of our headline products, data observatories. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://music.dataobservatory.eu/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;music.dataobservatory.eu&lt;/a&gt; will be a fully automated online service that every day collects, processes, cleans, and publishes scientifically valid data about European music.  Very soon after we will launch two other observatories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative and cultural sector, NGOs, most research institutions, data journalism teams are usually very small, and they do not have internal IT or data science capacities.  We would like to provide them a transparent, high quality, and fully open source solution to acquire data, process it without errors, document it and make sense of it. We would like to embrace the idea of open collaboration among creative enterprises, scientific researchers, NGOs, data journalists and policymakers with our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our work will comply with the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/opa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Open Policy Analysis&lt;/a&gt; standards developed by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitss.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkeley Initiative for Transparency in the Social Sciences&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cega.berkeley.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Center for Effective Global Action&lt;/a&gt; and the four principles of reproducible research: reviewability, replicability, confirmability and auditability.  We believe that these standards apply in reproducible finance, empirical evidence presentation in courts, or advocating sound policies and producing high-quality journalism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;help&#34;&gt;Do you want to help our start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to enter into the validation Lab of one of the best artificial intelligence incubators in the world very soon. Talented team members, letters of intents and assignments from organizations will give a lot of credibility to our start 
&lt;a href=&#34;/team&#34;&gt;Meet our team &amp;raquo;&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put as in contact with people who love to program in R and interested in automating business and social science research and primary data collection such as surveying. 
&lt;a href=&#34;#featured&#34;&gt;Check out what sort of code we create &amp;raquo;&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduce us to people who need data and information to make better informed decision and analysis in music, film, book publishing, photography services or socially responsible finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share contacts of data journalists who would like to develop stories from big survey programs like Eurobarometer, Afrobarometer and Lationbarometro, or base their storytelling on data and its visualizations. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://retroharmonize.satellitereport.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;See our survey harmonization examples &amp;raquo;&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks again for your good wishes and encouragements, and hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
